嗨，大家好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
Hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series
上次我们为Hazel设计了一个事件系统，如果你们还没看过那个视频，一定要去看看
so last time we planned an event system for Hazel, if you haven't seen that video, make sure that you check it out
我知道那是一个计划视频，你们可能会觉得它有点无聊，当然让我们直接写些代码吧
I know it's planning video, I know you might think that it's kind of boring, and it's let's just write some code, sure
但了解我们为什么要做出这种实际上正在做出的架构决策，这一点非常重要
but it's really important to understand why we're making these kind of architectural decisions that we actually are making
因为我们不理解那点，那么你们就无法学习如何开发游戏引擎
because we don't understand that, then well you're not gonna be able to learn how to actually write a game engine
那就是这期的全部内容，所以你们一定要去看看那期视频
which is what the series is all about, so definitely make sure you check that out
第二件事就是我想感谢所有让这个系列成为可能的赞助人
the second thing is I want to you just give a huge thank you to all the patrons that make this series possible
如果你们还没有支持这个系列的话，可以访问patreon.com/thecherno
if you guys aren't supporting the series, you can go to patreon.com/thecherno
你们将提前一周收到视频，并尽可能快地访问我写的Hazel引擎源码
you'll get episodes like a week early, as well as access to the source code of the Hazel engine as fast as I can write it
所以我的意思是，我的意思是，我们已经有了一个窗口，比如在屏幕上显示颜色
so I mean I mean we've already got like a window and like colors on the screen
并且所有那些东西在开发分支中都能正常运行
and all that stuff already working correctly kind of in that development branch
所以如果你们想继续，或者看看这是怎么回事
so if you want to kind of just go ahead, or see where this is heading
或者比如你们知道的，去实践一下实际的代码
or just you know get some gear hands on actual code
那比我们在这些视频中实际做的要深入得多
that is way more kind of further along than what we're actually doing in these videos
那绝对是做这件事最好的方法，所以说到这里，因为我们正在变成大型系统
that's definitely best plays to do that, so speaking of which because we're kind of getting into large systems
我想我应该稍微改变一下这个系列的形式
I thought that I would kind of change the format of this series a little bit
并且这是我们第一次看到这个，这个正在发生的变化
and this is kind of the first episode in which we kind of see this this, this change that is happening
所以在以前的视频中，我会在你们面前写代码
so in previous episodes what I would do is I'd kind of just write code in front of you
在某种程度上，我仍然会这样做，但这部分实际上会改变一下
and I and I still will do that to an extent, but that part is actually going to change
因为这个事件系统有相当数量的代码，并且这些视频
because this event system is a considerable amount of code, and these videos
我原本想保持在10到15或20分钟的时间
which I originally wanted to keep between kind of ten to fifteen to twenty minutes
结果现在变成了，大概是20到30分钟，我的意思是，有些视频甚至是30多分钟
are kind of becoming twenty to thirty minutes, and I mean, even thirty plus some episodes
这些的内容就有比较多，而我想让这个系列更容易理解，更容易消化
which is a little bit too much, I want this series to be a little bit more accessible, a little bit more consumable
并且我想更多的是关于实际的决定
and I guess more, so about the actual decisions
以及代码的原理，而实际上不是在你们面前写代码
and how the code works, rather than actually physically writing out the code in front of you
现在我可能会做一个关于我为什么做这个决定的视频，可以在另一个视频中讨论它
now I might I might make a video on why I made this decision, and we can talk about it maybe in another video
我并不希望我们在这个事件视频中讨论所有那些东西
I don't want to really just we were in this event video by talking about all that kind of stuff
但现在要改变的是，我所做的可能就是
but what's going to change now, and probably going forward is that instead what I've done is
我从我已经写好的私有开发分支代码中提取代码
I've taken code from that private development branch code that I've already written
已经测试过的，可能已经用了一段时间的代码
code that I've already tested, code that I've been probably using for a while at this point
并且把它合并到Hazel公共库中，然后我要有效地做的是
and I've kind of merged it into this Hazel public repository, and then what I'm going to effectively do is
当然要解释一下它的原理，并且也要回顾一下上一期前后的差异
explain how all of it works of course, and also kind of go through the diff of before and after the last episode
因为这个被推送到github，如果你们想的话，也可以去看看这个差异
now because this is pushed to github, you can actually look at the differential, if you want to
一旦这个视频公开，但即使在这个视频中，我也会详细介绍每一个变化
once this video goes public, but even in the video, I'll kind of go through each change
并解释实际发生的情况，不仅解释我为什么这么做，还要解释它的原理
and explain what's actually happened, and not just kind of why I've done this, but also how it works
所以我认为最终，我的意思是，就学习而言，这应该是完全一样的
so I think that ultimately, I mean, in terms of learning it should be exactly the same
这只会节省我很多打字的时间，这些东西不一定需要在你们面前敲出来
it's just gonna save a lot of me typing out stuff, that doesn't necessarily need to be typed out in front of you
我甚至不能谈论一些原因，比如使用一些不同的东西的原因
and I can't even talk about some of the reasons, why like some of the different different things that
我在写这段代码的时候也考虑过，因为这段代码都是我写的
I thought about while writing this code as well, because this code is all 100 Center in by me
所以我当然知道为什么我决定做某些事情而不是其他事情
so of course I know exactly why I've decided to do certain things and not other things
不管怎样，言归正传，让我们来看看这个事件系统
anyway, without further ado, let's just jump in and take a look at this event system
虽然我也有一些关于premake视频的修改，我相信在这里也会涉及到
although also I have a few amendments from the premake video, I believe that will also cover here
但希望这种新形式也能给你们带来乐趣
but hopefully this new format is also kind of entertaining for you guys to watch as well
我认为它实际上可能更容易观看，因为它不只是等待你们写代码
I think it actually might be easier to watch, because instead of just waiting for you to write a code
这一期更多的时间是花在我实际解释代码上，和讨论实际的代码，而不是实际谈论
it's more more of the episode is spent on me actually explaining the code, and talking about the actual code rather than physically talking about
所以不管怎样，让我们来看看吧，那么这儿是Event.h文件
so anyway, let's just jump in and take a look so here is the Event ummm file
我会过一遍我实际添加的内容，以便大家可以看到，基本上我所做的是改变
I'll kind of go through what I've actually added, so that you guys can see, essentially what I've done is
我在Hazel目录中创建了名为Events的文件夹，其中有四个文件
I've created this folder called Events inside the Hazel directory, and there's four files in here
这儿是Event.h头文件，它是整个事件系统的主文件
there's the Event.h header file, which is kind of the main file for this whole event system
然后我们有不同类型的事件，分成各自的文件
and then we've got different types of events, kind of split up into their own files
那么我们先来看看这些是如何运行的，然后我们来看看
so we'll kind of go through how these work first, and then we'll take a look at
这是一个创建事件的例子，看看接口是什么样子的
an example of actually creating an event, just to see what the api kind of looks like
我们可以用它来做什么呢，好了，那么我想让我们从顶部开始
and what we can actually do with it, okay, so let's start with the with the top I guess
此文件是全新的，因此无需像差异或任何东西一样显示
this file is completely new, so there's no need to show like a diff or anything
因为它是100%新的，所以我想说的第一件事就是包含
because it's 100% new, so the first thing I want to kind of talk of these includes
因为我不喜欢把这些东西包含在这样的文件中
because these are something that I really don't like including into files like this
因为string和functional都是C++标准库的东西
because string and also functional are just kind of C++ standard library stuff
这首先应该在预编译头文件中，但甚至在那之上
that first of all should really probably be in a pre-compiled header, but even above that
它们应该包含在Core.h中，所以我们需要很快地做的一件事
they should just be kind of included maybe in Core, so one thing that we need to get to doing very very quickly
因为这个引擎越往下发展，越难集成到预编译头文件
because it's just gonna be the further along this engine gets the harder is committing it to integrate later is precompiled headers
所以我们可能会在下一期或者在不久的将来看一看，好了
so we might take a look at that maybe in the next episode or sometime soon in the future, okay
所以我在这里写了一个很好的注释，只是为了解释事件系统目前是如何运行的
so I've written a nice little comment here, just to explain how the event system currently works
基本上这只是说，它是阻塞事件，对吧，这意味着这是设计的方式
and basically this just says, that it's blocking, right, which means that the way that this is designed
现在它没有被缓冲，事件没有被延迟
right, now is that it's not buffered, it's not kind of events aren't deferred
只要它们真的发生，只要鼠标被点击，就是那样
as soon as they actually happen like, as soon as the mouse is clicked, that's it
整个应用会停止，然后处理那个事件，这不像是那种
the whole application basically stops, and then processes that event, it's not kind of just like
让我们从事件中获取信息，将其推送到某个队列或某个缓冲区
let's get the information from the event, push it into some kind of queue or some kind of buffer
它们就会延迟，直到我们真正过到这个事件
and they kind of defer until until we actually go through the event
你们知道的，传递之类的，甚至通过某种事件总线之类的方式传递，不
you know, pass or whatever, and all kind of even propagate it through like some kind of event bus or something, no
它会立即发生，所以这只是一个简短的注释，解释这个设计目前是如何运行的
it just happens immediately, so this is just a little comment explaining that how the design currently works
也许在未来，我们可以将它们缓冲到某种事件总线中，好了，酷
and maybe in the future, we can buffer them into some kind of event bus, okay, cool
所以这是一切的核心，那么我们有这个Event类
so this is kind of the heart of everything, so we have this Event class
但我们也有一个enum，它基本上是一个EventType类，用来描述事件类型，对吧
but we also have an enum, which basically an EventType class, which describes the event type, right
所以我们有不同的事件类型，我把它们分成了不同的行
so we have different kind of event types, I've kind of split them up into separate lines
有些我们可能不会用到，但我们可以探索一下，比如这些
some of them we might not even use, we can explore using them, for example these ones
我不是百分之百地确定我真的想用，但是其他的都没问题
I'm not a hundred percent convinced that I actually want to use, but everything else is totally fine
并且你们也可以看到，因为这段代码是我已经写好的代码
and you can also see that, because this code is is code that I've already written
因为它是在Hazel开发分支中编写的
and because it's kind of written in the Hazel development branch
事实上，比如，我就完全忘记了写MouseScrolling
I'm able to actually, like I totally forgot about MouseScrollingfor example
如果我做了这个视频，就可能会忘记这个，稍后必须添加它
and if I made this video, I might have just forgotten about that, that I had to add it later
而是因为我已经使用这个代码一段时间了
but because I've kind of gone through, and been using this code for a while
它有点成熟了，我想我可以在这里合并代码
it's kind of matured, I guess to the point where the code that I can merge in here
给你们看实际上是最后版本，我的意思是，很明显将来会根据需要进行调整
and show you guys is actually somewhat, you know, final, I mean, obviously will tweak it in the future as need be
但这比我只是写我脑子里想到的东西更成熟一些
but it's a little bit more mature than me just kind of writing what's off the top of my head
或者在一些松散的设计上，就像你们知道的，像这些代码的实际使用
or bed on some loose design that hasn't been through, like you know, actually usage like this code has
因为我在Hazel开发分支中使用了很多这段代码
because I've been using this code quite a bit in that Hazel development branch
总之，我们有不同的事件类型，我们有所有的窗口事件
anyway, so we have different kinds of event types, we've got all the window events
现在这些实际的事件在它们相关的文件中实现
now these actual events are implemented in their relevant kind of files
那么ApplicationEvent会涵盖所有这些按键事件，包括KeyPressed和KeyReleased
so ApplicationEvent kind of covers all of these key events, covers KeyPressed and released
然后MouseEvent会包含所有这些事件，那么让我们看看ApplicationEvent
and then MouseEvent cover all this stuff, so let look at ApplicationEvent for example
你们可以看到，我们有WindowResizeEvent，我没有考虑，对吧
you can see, we have that like WindowResizeEvent, I don't think about, yeah, okay
AppRender，AppUpdate，AppTick以及WindowClose等等
AppRender, AppUpdate, AppTick, WindowClose and all that stuff
它都是在这里实现的，我们待会再看，那么这个enum基本上就像
it's all kind of implemented here, and we'll take a look at that later, so this enum basically is just like
嘿，知道吗，我们每个事件都有一个代码，你们可以看到
hey, you know, what is we have a code assigned to each event, you can see
它就是一个数字，None是0，而其他的就是从1到14
it's like a number essentially from like you know None is 0, but from 1 to like 14
这基本上只是说，这就是我的类型，也将意味着在未来
and this basically just says, this is what type I am, and will mean that in the future
因为我们需要能够分辨事件的类型
because we need to be able to kind of tell which type an event is
并且你们知道的，我们并不想使用dynamic_cast之类的东西
and you know, we don't really, don't want to use something like dynamic_cast
或运行时类型信息
or runtime type information for something as trivial as this
用一个整型id来关联所有东西会更简单，然后我们就可以处理它了
it's easier just to have an int id kind of associated with everything, and then we can deal with it
好了，那么这些事件分类，我们有这些的原因是我们可能想要过滤某些事件
okay, so event categories, the reason we have these is because we basically may want to filter certain events
那么换句话说，我从我的Application接收所有事件到某种事件分类
so in other words, I am receiving all events from my Application into some kind of an Event class
但我只关心键盘事件，对吧，这是一个很简单的场景
but I only care about the keyboard events, right, or free, like here's a really simple scenario
我想记录每个键盘事件或者每个鼠标事件，让我们看看鼠标事件吧
I would like to log every keyboard event now or every mouse event, let's see mouse event
因为有更多的鼠标事件，对吧，所以我真的要去看看
because there's more of them, right, so do I really have to go and check to see
如果EventType是Pressed或Released或Moved或Scrolled，那就有点烦人了
if the EventType is Pressed or Released or Moved or Scrolled, that's a little bit annoying
相反，我能做的是，我能说，嘿，你知道的，给我所有的鼠标事件
so instead, what I can do is, I can just say, hey, you know, what just give me all of the mouse events
因为我们有一些事件分类枚举，我们能够这样做
and because we have kind of this some event category enum, we're able to do that
因为这有点像，我想这几乎是一种特质，适用于特定的事件类型
because it's kind of like a, it's almost like a um a trait I guess, that's applied to certain event types
所以我们可以看到它们是什么，这实际上是一个位字段
so that we can actually see what they are, now this is a bit a bit field essentially
如果我们来到这儿，因为在Core.h定义它的，这就是全部代码了，对吧
if we just go to this, because I've just kind of defined it in the Core.h file, this is all it is, right
#define BIT(x) (1<<x)
define BIT(x) as just one shifted by x places
这只是说如果执行BIT(1)，你们会在位置上有一个比特
this just says that if you do a BIT(1) for example, you'll have essentially just a bit at position
你们知道的，10是位置0，等等
you know 1 0 would be position 0 and so on and so forth
这样我们就能得到一些位字段，对吧，我们特别想让它不局限于0 1 2 3 4是因为
so that we can actually end up with a bit of field, right, and the reason we want that specifically in not just 0 1 2 3 4 is because
我们可以将一个事件分成多个分类，比如，你们知道的
we have the ability for an event to go into multiple categories, so for example you know
键盘、鼠标和鼠标按钮事件都是输入事件
keyboard mouse and mouse button events are all input events
鼠标按钮事件是鼠标事件，对吧，键盘事件是键盘和输入事件
a mouse button event is a mouse event, right, a keyboard event is a keyboard and an input event
所以我们想要将多个分类应用到单个事件类型
so we have kind of we want to apply multiple categories to a single event type
所以我们需要创建一个位字段，这样我们就会设置多个位
so we need to create a bit field, so that we're gonna have multiple bits set
然后我们可以简单地取它们掩码，看看什么样的分类和事件
and then we can simply just mask them out, and see what what kind of category and event
或者一个事件实际上属于什么分类，在考虑这些宏的时候，我们会讲到它们
or what categories an event actually belongs to, during worried about these macros for a second, we'll get to them
让我们看一下这个实际的Event类，好了，那么首先，我想暂停一下
let's just take a look at this actual Event class, okay, so first of all, I just want to give a quick pause
你们看这有多棒，这是我第一次用这种形式制作视频
you see how how nice this is, like it is my first time doing a video in this format
但想象一下，如果我要写出所有这些代码，这个视频，可能会有一个小时那么长
but imagine if I had to write out all this code, this video, would be like an hour long
所以我认为这实际上是更好的，我甚至可能没有提到我做的很多事情
so I think that this is actually a lot better, and I might not even have mentioned a lot of the stuff I did
因为我的时间太紧了，所以我想做一个简短的评论
just because I would be you know stretched for time, so um yeah, I just wanted to make a quick comment that
实际上，我很喜欢这样，好了，不管怎样，那么我们有了这个Event类
I'm actually enjoying this, okay, anyway, so we have this Event class
后面也会讲到EventDispatcher，但本质上这是事件的基类
which will talk about the EventDispatcher later as well, but essentially this is a base class for events
另一个就是这个实际上存储的是布尔值m_Handle
the other thing this actually stores is the handle the boolean
因为我们需要能够看到一个事件是否被处理了
because we need to be able to see if an event has been handled or not
这样做的原因很大程度上是因为，当我们开始调度事件去处理不同的层时
the reason we have that is because further down the line, when we actually start to dispatch events to do various layers
例如，我们通常会说，我不想让这个事件被进一步传递
for example, it's pretty common for us to decide to say that, I don't want this to be propagated any further
那么比如鼠标点击事件，如果屏幕上有一个按钮，我们点击了鼠标
so a mouse click event for example, if we have a button on our screen, and we've clicked the mouse
鼠标落在按钮的范围内，然后就是那样，事件就被处理了
and the the mouse has fallen within the bounds of the button, then that's it, that event has kind of been handled
我们希望它使用该事件，以便它下面的层
we want it to consume that event, so that the layer underneath it
也许我们的游戏世界实际上并没有收到点击事件
which might be our game world doesn't actually receive a click event
因为按钮已经处理过了，所以这里需要这个
because of course, it's already been handled by the button, so that's why we need this here
当然在以后，当我们真正解决这个问题的时候
and of course in the future, when we actually get around this
你们会看到实际使用中的例子，至于这个IsInCategory，是一种非常简单的工具函数
you'll see real examples of this in use, IsInCategory, is a very simple kind of utility function
基本上就是问，嘿，你知道这个，你知道这个事件是这样的吗
which basically just asks, hey, you know is this, you know is this kind of, is this event for example
你知道一个MouseEvent或在给定分类中的吗
you know a MouseEvent or whatever is it in the given category
我们可以用这个快速过滤掉某些事件
and we can just use this quickly to filter out certain events
它所做的只是对实际分类做按位与运算，看看它是否真的属于那个分类
and all it does is just an and with the actual category to see, if it actually belongs to that category or not
当然，如果它返回0，这意味着它根本不在分类中
of course this will, if this returns zero, it means that it's not in the category at all
如果它返回的值不是0，它就会被捕获，它就会为真
if it returns anything other than zero, it will be caught, it'll be true
对，这意味着，它至少属于这个分类，也可能属于其他分类
right, which means that, it is at least in that category, might be in other categories as well
但至少在这个分类中，然后我们有很多虚函数，其中一些还是纯虚函数
but it's at least in this one, then we have a bunch of virtual functions, some of them being pure virtual
这意味着它们必须被实现，例如GetEventType, GetName, GetCategoryFlags
which means they must be implemented, so such as GetEventType, GetName, GetCategoryFlags
现在我还没有决定，我真的希望CategoryFlags是一个调试或任何东西
now I haven't decided whether or not, I actually want CategoryFlags to be a debug or anything
或者任何名字，它可能不是最大的开销
name definitely probably like will be, it's probably not the biggest overhead to have
但我们仍然因为它只是一个const char*，所以就是一个指向常量的指针
but still we because it's just a const char pointer, so it'll be like a pointer to constant
你们知道的，一种只读内存，不管怎样，但是，现在值得考虑一下
you know, kind of read-only memory, anyway, but mmm something to think about at the moment
我让它在所有配置中都是启用的，但这应该只用于调试
I've left it obviously enabled for all configurations, but it's this should really only be is for debugging
我不期望有必要去检索一个事件名称
I don't I don't expect ever being having the necessity to actually retrieve an event name
所以是的，但无论如何，纯虚函数，意味着，每个事件都必须实现ToString
so yes, but anyway, that pure virtual, which means, every event has to implement them ToString
默认只返回事件的名称，如果你们有更多细节想要打印的话
by default just returns the name of the event, obviously if you have more details that you want to be able to print
比如你们知道的屏幕，让我们去一个随机事件，一个WindowResizeEvent，可能想打印
such as you know monitor, let's go to a random event, a WindowResizeEvent, you might want to print
你们知道的，宽度和高度，就像我在这里做的，然后就可以重写ToString
you know, width and height, like I've done here, then you can override that ToString function
然后说，好了，这是一个WindowResizeEvent，并且我要把这个信息包含在它里面
and actually say, that okay, this is a WindowResizeEvent, and I'm including this information with it
好了，因为我有点，你们知道，ToString绝对只是一个调试的东西
okay, because I've kind of, you know, this the ToString is definitely a debugging only thing
我并没有真正注意到性能或类似的事情
I haven't been really kind of attentive to performance or anything like that
我只是在这里使用stringstream，并不是说stringstream的性能很差
I'm just using stringstream here, not that the stringstream is terrible for performance
但很明显，它有能力分配内存，但同样，我们不关心这里的性能
but obviously it has the ability to allocate memory, but again, we don't care about performance here at all
因为这些都是调试，打印事件信息
because all this is is a debug, kind of a print the event information
因为我不确定我的事件是否正常运行，对吧
because I'm not sure my events are working correctly or whatever, right
不应该被实际的游戏使用，运行时只用于调试，好了，酷
should never be used by actual game, runtime for anything other than debugging, okay, cool
继续，是的，所以这些默认必须实现，你们知道
moving on, yeah so these have to be implemented this by default, you know it
Event类为你们提供了一个默认的ToString，它只是Event的名称
the Event class provides you with just a default kind of ToString, which is just the name of the Event
但你们当然有能力重写它，就那样，那就是整个Event类
but of course you have the ability to override that, that's it, that's the whole Event class
那么在进入Dispatcher之前，让我们看看Event是什么样子的
so before we get into the Dispatcher, let's just actually look at what an Event might look like
所以我想我可能，嗯，也许KeyEvent会是比较值得关注的东西
so I think I might um maybe like a KeyEvent would be something better to look at
所以KeyEvent非常简单，很明显，当我们在键盘上按键时，KeyEvents就会运行
so a KeyEvent is very simple, obviously KeyEvents work, when we kind of press things on our keyboard
如果我按下键盘上的一个按键，那就是KeyPressEvent
so if I press a key on my keyboard, that's a KeyPressEvent
当我从键盘上释放按键时，那是一个KeyReleasedEvent
when I release the key from my keyboard, that's a KeyReleasedEvent
现在这些这些KeyEvents有一些共同之处，对吧
now these these KeyEvents have certain things in common, right
也就是被按下或释放的按键代码，对吧，不管它是按下还是释放
namely the key code of what has been pressed or released, right, whether it's press or released
那应该是它自己的事件类型，但这些事件之间的按键代码是通用的
that's should be its own event type, but the key code is common between those events
这就是为什么我做了一个基类KeyEvent，它包含按键代码
which is why I've made a base class called KeyEvent, which contains the key code
现在按键释放可能不需要其他任何东西，除了它是一个KeyReleasedEvent
now key released probably shouldn't need anything else, apart from just the fact that it's a KeyReleasedEvent
因此按键已经释放，但按键按下时也应该有是否
therefore the key has been released, but a key pressed should also have whether or not
本次按键是一个RepeatedEvent，这意味着
the key is a RepeatedEvent, what that means is that
当我按下一个按键时，通常会发生什么取决于操作系统和驱动程序等等
when I press a key, what happens usually depending on the operating system and the drivers and all that
但通常当我按下一个按键时，它会发送给操作系统，发送一个KeyPressedEvent，对吧
but usually when I press a key, it sends the operating system, sends a KeyPressedEvent, right
然后等待一会儿，然后它发送一堆按键重复事件，你们可以看到这一点
and then waits like a little bit, and then it sends a bunch of key repeat events, you can see this in action
如果我点击某个地方，然后按a键，你们就会看到
if I just kind of click somewhere, and I press the a key, you'll see that there's going
我会在这里按住a键，坚持一会儿，你们就会看到
and I'm gonna press, and hold the a key in a minute here, you'll see, there's like
它会添加字母a会立即出现，然后会有停顿
it'll add the letter a will appear immediately, then there'll be a pause
然后它会打印出一堆，对吧，那么，是的，再打印一次a，然后剩下的就在那儿，对吧
and then it will print a bunch of them, right, so, yeah, again a, and then they're, there the rest, right
所以第一个是KeyPressedEvent，然后其他的基本上是KeyRepeatEvent
so the first one is a KeyPressedEvent, and then there's other ones are essentially KeyRepeatEvents
所以我们也希望能够接受那点
so we want to be able to kind of also take that
所以那就是KeyPressedEvent和KeyReleasedEvent除了名称之外的不同
so that's how a PressEvent might be different from a ReleasedEvent other than the name
但因为它们有相同的按键代码，我在这里实际上做的是，创建了这种KeyEvent基类
but because they have that key code in common, what I've actually done here is, I've created this kind of KeyEvent base class
正如你们看到的，它只包含一个按键代码，就那样，还有一个受保护的构造函数
as you can see, which just contains a key code, that's it, it's also got a protected constructor
因为没有别的东西可以构造它，然后它把它放在一起，用于按键代码
because nothing else can construct it, and then it's got it just together for that key code
显然，我们不需要设置按键代码，因为当事件被构造时，那就会被设置
obviously we don't need to set the key code, because that happens, when the event gets constructed
但我们确实想要得到它，然后我们有一个宏来实现这个类分类判断
but we do want to get it, and then we have a macro which implements this class category thing
我们待会再讲宏，因为还有更多，好了，那么这儿还有个KeyPressedEvent
we will talk about the macros in a minute, because there's more, okay, so a KeyPressedEvent
所以这是一个抽象事件，你们不应该能够创建一个KeyEvent，不能
so essentially this is kind of like an abstract event, you shouldn't really be able to make a KeyEvent, you really can't
我是说，它有一个受保护的构造函数
I mean, it's got a protected constructor
所以你们不能在任何东西中创建这个类，除了它的派生类
so you won't be able to make this class in anything other than a class that derives from it
所以KeyPressedEvent是一个实际的事件，对吧
so KeyPressedEvent is an actual event, right
我们将在引擎中看到它基本上有一个keycode和一个repeatCount
that we'll see in our engine it's basically got a keycode, and a repeatCount
所以我还没有决定，我们是否需要记录统计次数
so I haven't really decided whether or not, we want to keep track of the amount of times
就是一个按键是否重复触发，通常就像这样，就像一个布尔值
that a key has been repeated, usually like essentially like this could act like a boolean
所以你们知道，意思就是，如果这个是0，那么它就不是，它就不是一个重复事件
so you know, I mean, if this is zero, then it has not been, it's not a repeat event
这是我第一次按下按键，但之后就像
it's the first time that keys been pressed, but then the kind of remaining like
如果不是0，也就是1
if it's anything other than when other than the zero, which might be one
如果它被重复了20次，如果它被重复了20次，或者它可能只是1次
if it's been repeated all like twenty, if it's been repeated twenty times, or it could just be one
即使它已经重复了20次，这取决于我们如何实现它
even if it has been repeated twenty times depending on how we implement it
那意味着它是一个重复事件，所以那就是，比如整个KeyRepeatEvent的东西非常非常有用
that just means, it's a repeat event, so that's really, like this whole KeyRepeatEvent stuff is really really useful
因为如果，你们知道的，如果你们在游戏中制作菜单之类的东西
because if, you know, if you're making something like a menu in game
那么你们的菜单里有四个选项，举个例子，不支持鼠标操作
so you have like four options in your menu, and the mouse isn't in use for example
你们只能用方向键进入菜单，很明显，你们知道
you just want to use the arrow keys to go down the menu, obviously like you know
举个例子，你们可能想，可能需要
for as an example, you might want to only, you might want to
强制用户多次按方向键来完成某项任务
force the user to actually press the arrow key multiple times to go through something
而不是按下按键并保持，按传统来说，如果你们只是处理一个KeyPressedEvent
instead of being able to press and hold it, traditionally, if you just handle a PressedEvent
并且你们可以看到，直到它被释放，循环遍历菜单选项，它会非常快地循环下去
and you see that, until it's released go cycle through the menu options, that'll keep looping really quickly
即使用户快速按下按键，它可能仍然会发送两个事件，这很糟糕
and even if the user presses the key quickly, it might actually still send two events, that's bad
因为设置的方式是，正如你们之前看到的，我输入一个A按键，它就可以发送事件
because the way that this is set up is, as you saw, with me typing A key it will kind of just send the event
稍等一下，然后就发送一堆重复事件，因为这是大多数OS的处理方式，这个你们可以
wait a bit, and then send a bunch of repeat events, because that's how most of operate system's handle, this you could just
你们甚至不需要担心菜单的重复计数
you don't, you don't even need to worry about repeat count for menus
因为你们可以看到，你们知道，很明显有差距，所以你们就可以
because you could just see that, you know, obviously there's that gap, so you can just kind of
你们可以自然地等待，直到它给用户足够的时间来释放它
you can just kind of wait naturally, until it kind of that will give the user man enough time to release it
如果他们不想浏览多个菜单选项，那么基本上你们可以看到
if they don't want to go through multiple menu options, and then essentially you could just see that
我会让它自然运行，也就是说，你们使用？，它会下降，等待一段时间，然后一直下降
I'll just let it naturally work, which means that, you use the president downer, it goes down, waits a bit, and there goes boom boom boom, all the way down
可能是循环或者别的，不管怎样，那只是一个用例场景
and maybe loops or whatever, so that's just a use case scenario, anyway
那就是重复的想法，我们在这里实现了一个ToString函数
um that's kind of the idea with repeats, we've implemented a ToString function here
它重写了我们的ToString，并且基本上看到了那一点，它将只打印已按下的队列
which overrides our ToString, and just essentially sees that, this will just print which queue has been pressed
还有重复次数，然后我们有这个EVENT_CLASS_TYPE宏，它实现了我们所有的功能
and also the amount of times, and then we have this EVENT_CLASS_TYPE macro, which implements all of our functions
那么让我们讨论这些宏，现在有了EVENT_CLASS_CATEGORY和EVENT_CLASS_TYPE
so let's talk about these macros, now we have EVENT_CLASS_CATEGORY and EVENT_CLASS_TYPE
它们存在的原因是我们需要实现这三个纯虚函数
the reason these exist is because we need these three things implemented
现在事件类型名称和分类标志是如此微不足道，我的意思是，我们真的不需要它们
now event type name and category flags are so trivial, that I mean, we don't really need them
分类标志显然需要指定分类，但命名事件类型
now category flags obviously does need the category to be specified, but name an event type
我的意思是，名称是事件类型，输入这些很痛苦
I mean the name is the event type, and it's just a pain to kind of type all this
那么我们不需要输入所有这些代码，我将展示给你们
so instead of us having to type essentially all of this code, I would I'll show you
忘记了一个KeyEvent，你们知道如果我想用这个东西
what it wouldn't look like forgot a KeyEvent, you know if I wanted to employ this stuff
我得说，我的意思是，看看这些东西，我们还需要一个静态类型
I'd have to basically say, I mean, look at all this stuff, we also need a static type
我们马上就会讲到，但基本上我想说的是
which we'll talk about in a minute, but basically what I would need to say is that
我需要一个静态函数，它返回这个事件的类型
I would need a static function, which returns the type of this event
这是一个KeyPressedEvent，如果我们去到Event类
now this is a KeyPressedEvent, which if we go to our Event class
它是这个KeyPressed事件，也就是EventType::KeyPressed
it's this KeyPressed event, which would just be EventType KeyPressed
我需要一个虚函数，它返回这种静态类型，我们一会儿就会知道为什么需要它
I need to have a virtual function, which returns this static type, and we'll see, why we need that in a minute
然后我就不需要这个名字了，也可能是类似的名字
um and then I wouldn't need this name, which again would probably be something like that
因此，不用在每个实现中复制和粘贴此代码
so instead of copying and pasting this code in every single implemention
我刚刚实现了一个可以使用的宏
I've just implemented a macro that I can use
就是这个EVENT_CLASS_TYPE，然后是KeyPressed，也就是这个类型
which just says EVENT_CLASS_TYPE, and then KeyPressed, which is this type
就这样，然后显然它会做的是，填空，将它字符串化为名字
and that's it, and then obviously what it will do is, fill in the blanks it, will stringify it for the name
我的意思是，就是这样，所以说，这些静态类型的想法是什么，为什么我们需要它们
and I mean, that's about it, so that being said, what is the idea with these static types, why do we need them well
我们希望能够在运行时检查，这个KeyPressedEvent是什么类型，对吧
we want to be able to at runtime check to see, which type this KeyPressedEvent is, right
所以显然，我们需要一个函数，返回它是什么类型的事件，现在这个不一定是成员函数
so obviously we need a function, that returns which event type it is, now this does not have to be a member function
它可以只是一个静态函数，因为如果我们看到KeyPressedEvent类型之类的
it can just be a static function, because if we see KeyPressedEvent type or whatever
我们不需要一个KeyPressedEvent类的实例来实际查看它是什么类型
we don't need to have an instance of the KeyPressedEvent class to actually see what type it is
很明显，KeyPressedEvent总是一个KeyPressed事件，不管实例是什么
obviously KeyPressedEvent is always going to be a KeyPressed event, no matter what the instance is
现在，我们之所以需要一个非基于实例的，是因为它是一个虚拟的，对吧
now the reason we need a non instance based one is specifically a virtual one, right
这个重写了一个虚函数，我们之所以需要它，是因为如果我们只有一个事件基类，对吧
this overrides a virtual function, the reason we need that is because if, we just have an event base class, right
如果我们把它看成这是一个多态问题
if we're just treating it kind of this is like a polymorphic kind of thing
我们只是，只是有一个指向Event的引用或指针，我们希望能够看到
we're just we just have a reference or a pointer to an Event, we want to be able to see
它实际是什么类型，你们知道的，我们可以执行Event->GetEventType
what type it actually is, so we can do Event, you know, GetEventType
它会返回它实际是什么类型的事件，它的一个实现场景是实际的EventDispatcher
and it will return which event type it actually is, one implementation scenario for this is the actual EventDispatcher
你们可以在Dispatch函数中看到它的作用
you can see what it does here in the Dispatch function
它检查当前尝试调度的事件类型是否与此模板参数匹配
is it checks to see which event type the current event that we're trying to dispatch is whether or not it matches this template argument
因为这是一个静态函数
and because this is a static function
我们可以只使用T::GetStaticType，现在这儿没有类型安全来确保它是事件
we can just do T::GetStaticType, now there's no type safety here to make sure it's an event for example
但它已经有了，但你们可以看到，显然因为它只是一次编译
but it can already have, but that aside you can see that, obviously uh because it's just one compile
如果这是一个事件之类的，它会得到静态类型，你们可以在这里看到
if this is an event or anything, that has get static type, but anyway, you can see here
我们可以在Event引用和模板参数之间进行比较，事件引用可以是任何事件，和模板参数
we're able to do this comparison between an Event reference, which is just which could be any event, and this template argument
然后，如果在这种情况下的话，那么这个调度器将它调度到适当的事件，或者适当的函数
and then if so example in this case, this dispatchable dispatch it to the appropriate event, or to the appropriate function essentially
稍后我们会更详细地讨论这个EventDispatcher
and we'll talk about the EventDispatcher in more detail a little bit later
但不管怎样，那就是我们需要这两个的原因
but anyway, that's why we need these two
然后就是GetName，你们知道的，返回名称，通常是为了调试
and then the GetName, you know, just returns the name for usually for debugging purposes
所以这三个都很容易通过这个宏实现，EventClassCategory也是如此
so all these three are easily implemented with this one macro, same with the EventClassCategory
而不是我们需要，你们知道的，就是virtual int GetCategoryFlags() const override之类的
instead of us kind of having to, you know, type out, you know, virtual int GetCategoryFlags() const override whatever
可以很容易看到EVENT_CLASS_CATEGORY，就这两个，好了，我已经把它们放在一起了
we can easily just see EVENT_CLASS_CATEGORY, these two, okay, I've ordered them together
因为键盘事件也是一个重要的事件，好了，我在基类中实现了这个
because of course a keyboard event is also an important event, okay, and I've implemented this in the base class
不管怎样，因为KeyPressed和KeyReleased事件都是这两个
because a KeyPressed and Released event are both of these, anyway
所以我不需要在它们自己的类中实现它们，好了
so I don't need to implement them in their own kind of classes, okay
那是KeyPressedEvent, KeyReleaseEvent是相同的，除了？，没有repeatCount
that's the KeyPressedEvent, KeyReleaseEvent is identical except Issa's and does not have that repeatCount
显然它只有一个KeyReleasedEvent，类型是KeyReleased而不是KeyPressed，好了
and obviously it's just got a KeyReleasedEvent, and the type is KeyReleased instead of KeyPressed, okay
那就是KeyEvent，现在鼠标事件(MouseEvent)完全一样，我的意思是
that is that is the KeyEvent, now mouse events exactly the same, I mean
你们可能已经知道，如何写这些MouseMovedEvent，好了
you guys probably already understand, how to write these a MouseMovedEvent, okay
一个事件，它有x和y，也就是鼠标当前的位置
is an event, it's got x and y, which is the location of the mouse as it currently stands
我们有获取器，有ToString，它打印MouseMovedEvent和坐标
we've got getters for that, we've got a ToString, which prints MouseMovedEvent along with the coordinates
然后我们会实现这两个东西，它们实现MouseMoved类类型
and then we will we've implemented these two things, which implement the MouseMoved class type
它给了我们所有的类型信息，然后还有EVENT_CLASS_CATEGORY，告诉我们分类
which gives us all of our type information, and then also the EVENT_CLASS_CATEGORY, which tells us which category thing
就这样，然后我们就把所有的东西都存储起来了，你们可以快速记下Hazel引擎
and that's it, and then we're storing everything, you quick note for the Hazel kind of engine
我采用的编码风格是先公开的东西，然后私有的东西
the coding style that I've kind of adopted is public stuff first, and then private stuff
原因是当你们看一个类，你们知道的，让我们看看，在用Hazel引擎运行一个游戏
the reason is when you kind of look at a class, and you know you, let's just see, you're running a game with the Hazel engine
并且想很快看到，你们能用这个接口做什么
and you want to quickly see, what you can actually do with the api
显然你们不关心私有的实现细节，对吧
obviously you don't care about the implementation details which are private, right
你们首先想看到的是实际可以使用的，对吧
what you want to see first is what you can actually use, right
所以这就是为什么对我来说更有意义的是，所有公共的东西都先写
so that's why it makes more sense to me to just say, all the public stuff gets written first
然后私有的东西只有我们作为开发者才感兴趣
and then the private kind of stuff that is only in that is only kind of interesting to us as developers
当人们开发Hazel引擎的时候，你们知道，这有点，我们还是不谈这个了
as days people developing the Hazel engine, you know, that's kind of, let's just not talk about that
因为如果我们使用Hazel引擎，我们想看看我们能使用什么
because if we're actually using the Hazel engine, we want to actually see what we can use
而不是实现细节，这我们不关心，好了，MouseScrolledEvent完全一样的，对吧
and not implementation details, which we don't care about, okay, ScroledlEvent exactly the same, right
我们有偏移量，也就是我们滚动了x和y
we have our offset, which is essentially where we've kind of scrolled both x and y
因为我们可以在一些鼠标上进行水平滚动
because there is horizontal scrolling that we can do on some mice
然后这个显然打印了所有信息也实现了所有类型的东西
and then this obviously prints all of the information implements all the type stuff as well
事件，你们知道的，这是一个实际的基类，然后我们有ButtonPressed和ButtonReleased
but an event again, you know, this is an actual base class, and then we have ButtonPressed, ButtonReleased
我们的按钮被存储在这里，这是受保护的，所以我们不能创建这个事件
we have our button being stored here, this is protected, so that we can't create this event
只有MouseButtonPressedEvent和MouseButtonReleasedEvent能创建那个
only the MouseButtonPressedEvent and ReleasedEvent can create that
然后我们会像往常一样实现其他所有东西
and then we have everything else implemented kind of as usual
你们知道了吧，ApplicationEvent有WindowResizeEvent和WindowCloseEvent
you get the drift, ApplicationEvent has things like WindowResize, WindowCloseEvent
WindowCloseEvent很简单，什么都没有，它在EventCategoryApplication中
WindowCloseEvent is really simple, has absolutely nothing, it's in the Application EventCategory
它实际上只是，嘿，我是一个WindowCloseEvent，根本不需要任何数据
and all it really is is just, hey, I'm a WindowCloseEvent, it doesn't need any data at all
WindowResizeEvent有我们被调整到的宽度和高度，然后我们还有这四个事件
ResizeEvent has the width and height that we've been resized to, and then we have also these four events
我不确定，如果我要使用，但我们有TickEvent，UpdateEvent和RenderEvent
which I'm not sure, if I'm going to use yet, but we have TickEvent, UpdateEvent and RenderEvent
这是如果我们想要，更新渲染和时钟函数以事件的形式传播，这是可行的
this is if we would like our kind of, you know, update render and tick functions to actually be propagated as events, which is doable
但是，如果我们试图像学究一样，正确地使用事件系统
but again, if we were trying to be really like pedantic about our correct kind of event system usage
那么也许一切都应该是一个事件，因此你们知道，因此我们应该把它作为一个事件来实现
then maybe everything should be an event, and thus you know, thus we should have this implemented as an event
但因为它们是某种，你们知道的，所以是实际应用程序的固有特性
but because they're kind of, you know, so, so intrinsic to an actual application
我觉得这应该是硬编码的，就像你们知道的，这三个
I feel that maybe this should just be hard coded, that's just like you know these three are like you know
实际的非模块化事件，它们总是存在的，你们可以选择实现它们，也可以不必实现它们
actual non-modular events, they're always present, and you can choose to implement them or you don't have to
但它们已经为你们准备好了，你们不需要首先把它们当作事件来接收
but they're kind of already there for you, you don't need to first receive them as an event
然后把它们分配给一个已经调用过的函数，我倾向于这样做
and then dispatch them to a function there already called, and I'm I'm leaning towards doing it that way
但以防万一，我们确实有这三个事件，好了，就这样
but just in case, we do have these three events over here, okay, so that is that
实际上，那就是我添加的4个文件，用于整个事件系统，它们是Dispatcher
that's what I've actually added these kind of four four files, which are for your full event system, are the dispatcher
我们快速讲一下，那么Dispatcher是一种基于事件类型调度事件的方法
let's quickly talk about that, so the Dispatcher is a is a way for us to actually dispatch events based on their type
很容易，所以如果我们接收到一个事件
really easily, okay, so if we're, if we receive an event
我们知道，我们自己的事件函数被调用，将作为Event引用接收它，这意味着
and we you know, our own event function gets called, we will we will be receiving it as an event reference, which means that
它可以是任何类型的事件，我们不知道它是什么，所以我们可以写
it could be any type of event, we have no idea what it is, so what we can do is we can actually write
我们可以用刚刚接收到的事件创建该类的一个实例
we can create an instance of this class with the event that we've just received
然后我们可以用不同的事件函数多次调用这个Dispatch函数
and then we can call this Dispatch function a bunch of times with with a different event function
这个事件函数就像你们看到的，它是一个std::function，对吧
and this event function is as you can see, it's an it's a std::function, all right
它返回布尔，并接受T&，所以T在这种情况下可以是任何事件类型
which returns bool, and takes in T reference, so T in this case could be any event type
像WindowResizeEvent一样，我们可以在WindowResizeEvent中看到bool Dispatch()
like WindowResizeEvent, so we could see bool Dispatch in a WindowResizeEvent
然后我们可以在引擎的某个地方实现一个函数，通常在同一个类中
and then we could implement a function somewhere in our engine, usually in the same class
你们实际上处理的是这个事件，但本质上是一个函数，接收
as you've actually are handling is this event in, but essentially a function that takes in
你们知道，一个WindowResizeEvent，然后返回一个布尔值，然后使用基本上通过
you know, a WindowResizeEvent, and then returns a boolean, and then uses basically passes through
如果你们要调度的事件本质上与这个函数的类型匹配，那么它就会运行那个函数
and if the event that you're trying to dispatch matches the type of this function essentially, then it will actually run that function
它会用那个事件调用那个函数，否则，它就不会，就是这样，它很容易使用
it'll call that function with that event, otherwise, it just won't, right, that's really it, it's really easy to use
将来我们可能会看到它的实际作用，当我们开始从Window类接收事件时
we'll see it in action probably in the future, when we actually start, you know, receiving events from like the Window class or whatever
但这是一种很简单的方法让我们不必说
but that's kind of just a really easy way for us to actually be able to not have to say
你们知道，如果事件类型为KeyEvent，则手动开启事件功能，就是KeyPressed
you know, manually now on event function if the event type is KeyEvent, called the KeyPressed
你们知道的，在KeyPressed函数中，也可以将其转换为KeyPressedEvent
you know, on KeyPressed function with the in your, and also cast this to it, you know, to the to a KeyPressedEvent
因为它目前只是一个普通的基础事件，这个可以自动处理那个
because it's currently just a normal base event, this kind of automates that
它使我们的客户端代码看起来非常简单，最后，我们有一个小小的输出流操作符
it makes our code in the client side look really simple, and then finally, we have a little output stream operator
这是为我们的日志库而存在的，所以我们可以很容易地在事件上调用ToString
this exists for our logging library, so that we can easily just call ToString on the event
我们就能很容易地记录事件，等下我们就会看到，好了，那是我添加的所有新文件
and we'll be able to log events really easily as we'll see in a minute, okay, that's all of the new files that I've added
我将带你们看一看我修改过的现有文件的区别
I'm going to take you through the diff of the kind of existing files that I've modified
我已经建立了一个非常非常简单的监控系统的例子，请随意盘它，并做出你们自己的例子
I've set up a very very simple example of a surveillance system, feel free to just play around with it, and make your own examples
或者只是玩玩，玩玩，这样你们就能更好地理解它是如何运行的
or just you know, play, just play around with it, so that you can understand, how it works a little bit better
显然，当我们添加一个Window类时，我们开始接收这些真实的事件
obviously as we add like a Window class, and we actually start receiving these real events
实际输入事件会大量使用这个系统，但现在，它只是供我们使用的
like real input events will be heavily using this system, but for now, it's kind of just there for us to use
所以让我们看看所有的差异吧，我在这里用的是Beyond Compare
so yeah let's just take a look at all the diffs, so I'm using Beyond Compare here
我刚运行了git difftool，我设置了 Beyond Compare作为我的difftool
I've really just run git difftool,  and I've set up the  Beyond Compare as my devtool
我已经做了一个完整的目录差异，所以这就是所有改变的东西，那么让我们看一下
I've done a full directory diff, so this is everything that's changed, so let's take a look
所以如果你们认为我在premake文件中做的一些事情来自上一期，你们可能已经意识到
so if you think a few things that I did in the premake file is from last episode, you might you might have realized
我加了一点备注，这不是在上一期，这是在premake的那期
add a little I added a little note, this wasn't in the last episode, this was in the premake episode
但我加了一点说明，对于这个，我们不需要硬编码
but I added a little note saying that, we don't actually have to hardcode this
现在在premake中，有一个systemversion:latest
there is a systemversion:latest, now in premake
我们可以直接使用，我们只需使用最新的系统版本
that we can just use, and our just use the latest system version
所以那就是我们想要的，所以我对Sandbox和Hazel项目都做了更改
so that's what we want, so I've changed that for both the Sandbox and the Hazel projects
然后我添加到了Hazel的includedirs，还添加了src目录
and then I've also added into it the includedirs for Hazel, I've also added the src directory
这只是为了让我们可以，你们知道，做这样的事情
this is just so that we can, you know, do stuff like
因为你们知道，这个Event在Events文件夹中，就是Event.h文件
because you know, this Event is inside the Events folder, this Event.h file
但我不想回到上一级目录，然后进入Core之类的
but I don't really want to go back a directory and go into Core or whatever
我希望能够从src目录开始
I want to be able to just start from the src directory
我的部分总是与包含Hazel的src目录相关
and always do my parts kind of relative to that src directory which contains Hazel
所以如果我们看一下这里的所有文件，你们可以看到，我们有一个src目录
so if we look at what all files here, you can see, we have a src directory
事实上，我在这里添加了这个src目录，这意味着一切都可以与此相关
and the fact that I've added this src directory here means that everything is about everything can be relative to this
这意味着我可以写Hazel/Core.h，就像那样，真的很干净
which means I can just write Hazel/Core like that, and it's really clean
也就是说，如果把这个文件移动到其他文件夹
and also means that, if this file moves into a different folder
我不需要重做所有的路径，因为所有路径都是相对于这个的
I don't have to redo all my paths, everything's going to be always relative to this
好了，所以那就是我对premake文件所做的所有更改
okay, so that's all the changes that I made to the premake file
显然我已经运行了GenerateProjects.bat文件，实际上我已经重新生成了所有这些项目
obviously I have ran the GenerateProjects.bat file, and I've actually regenerated all of these projects
也就是说，这两个发生了变化，那么，好了，Application.h，所以我在这儿包含了Event.h
which means that, that's why these two have changed, so yeah, okay, Application, so I've included Events here
可能不需要在Application.h中包含，应该是在Application.cpp中
probably didn't need to do it necessarily in the Application file in the header file, could be done in the cpp file
但我在这里所做的只是，我们马上就会运行这段代码
but all I've really done here is just, and we'll run this code in a minute
但我刚创建了一个小测试，以及WindowResizeEvent，然后用HZ_TRACE记录它
but I've just created a little test,  I've created a WindowResizeEvent like that, and then I've just logged it using HZ_TRACE
因为我们已经添加了这些输出流操作符，应该能够这样做，好了，酷
and because we've added those output stream operators, we should just be able to do that, okay, cool
然后Core.h中，添加了BIT宏，这样我们就能很容易地定义位字段，然后进入日志系统
and then in Core.h, I added that BIT macro, just so that we can define bit fields easily, and then into our logging system
我还添加了这个包含，也就是spdlog的输出流操作符
I have added this include, which is the output stream operator for spdlog for speed log
这样我们就能使用我们的自定义，这样我们就能像事件中那样记录自定义类型
so that we can actually use our kind of custom, so that we can log custom types like in our events
好了，就这样，就这样，那就是所有的变更，所以在这里做一个小测试，所做的就是
okay, that's it, that's all, that's changed, so to do a little test here what I've done is
同样，我得到了WindowResizeEvent，只是创建了一个WindowResizeEvent，记录它
again, I've got this WindowResizeEvent, just creates a WindowResizeEvent, and then we just log it
如果我运行这段代码，你们可以看到我的WindowResizeEvent被正确记录，一切都很好
if I run this code, you can see that I get my WindowResizeEvent being logged correctly, and everything is great
如果我做了别的事，你们知道的，为什么不能，例如，看，你们知道
if I do something else, you know, why couldn't for example, see, you know
这个在。。。IsInCategory，我不知道，可能是Application吧，然后打个trace日志
is this in the, IsInCategory, I don't know, Application, then we could trace it
否则的话，你们知道的，如果它在，让我们试试别的分类
otherwise, you know, if it's in, let's just try other category
那个不在的话，EventClass，应该是EventCategoryInput
that is not in, EventClass, EventCategoryInput
所以这应该只记录一次，对吧，我可以在这里放一个断点
so this should only log it once, right, and I can put a break point here
为了验证实际发生了什么，你们可以看到它在那个分类中
just to verify what actually happens you can see it is in that category
那么我们实际上就记录了它，但它不在这个分类中的话
so we actually log it, and it's not in this category
那么就忽略它，最后，它会被记录一次，好了，所以那就是想法，它真的很简单
so we skip it, and in the end, it gets logged once, ok, so that's kind of the idea, it's really quite simple
我们有一个非常基本的测试，显然当我们开始实现一个Window类时
and we've got a very basic test, obviously as we start to implement a Window class
这可能是我们的下一个主要任务，之后，可能是一些其他的事情，比如预编译头
which is probably gonna be our next major thing, after, maybe some other things like precompiled headers
会正确地使用这个事件系统，你们会看到它完全运行起来，好了
will actually start using this event system properly, and you'll see it fully in action all right
所以我希望你们喜欢这个视频，告诉我你们对这种新形式的看法，我真的很喜欢
so I hope you guys enjoyed this video, let me know what you think of this new format, I really like it
这就结束了，超过30分钟，不管怎样，想象一下，如果写所有这些代码，可能需要一个小时
this ended up over 30 minutes, anyway, imagine, if I'd written all this code, it were probably an hour
我可能真的很无聊，我只是我真的很开心，这也让我感觉轻松了很多
I probably be really boring, and I'm just I'm really happy, and it this just makes it easier for me as well
因为我没有集中注意力，也没有忘记任何事情
because instead of concentrating, and making sure that I'm not forgetting anything
写正确的代码，我的压力就会小一些
and typing the right code, again, I'm less stressed about that
我可以花更多的时间来解释这些代码的作用
and I'm actually I can actually spend more time explaining what the code actually does
对我来说，这更有趣，可能对你们更有用
and like to me, that's more fun and possibly more useful to you guys
如果你们注意到有什么不同以及从中得到什么信息，请告诉我
let me know if you notice any differences in kind of how this goes and the information you're getting out of this
但不管怎样，我希望你们喜欢这个视频，如果你们喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
but anyway, I hope you guys enjoy this video, if you did, you can hit that like button
如我之前所说的，你们可以访问patreon.com/thecherno来支持这个系列
you can have support this series by going to patreon.com/thecherno as I said earlier
你们将可以访问我们已经拥有Window类的私有存储库
you will get access to that private repository in which we already have a Window class
我按了f5，抱歉，我们已经有了Window类
I just hit f5, I'm sorry, in which we already have the Window class
所有这些事件都在使用，所以你们希望看到这个事件系统像今天这样运行
as well as all these events being used, so you want to see this event system in action like today
你们可以去帮助支持这个系列，并且那些明显有助于支持这个系列的东西
you can just go and help support the series, and of what obviously does help actually support this series
所以你们会看到更多的视频，我们有一个很好的小社区
so you'll see more episodes, and it's just a good little community we have
这使得这个系列成为可能，这是了不起的
which makes this series possible, which is awesome
因为我喜欢为你们做这些视频，下次我真的想做预编译头文件
because I love making these videos for you guys, next time I really want to do precompiled headers
然后在那之后，我想我们可能最终会开始讨论，我们如何实现Window类
and then after that, I think we'll probably finally be able to start talking about, how we can implement a Window class
因为在屏幕上出现一些东西，会很好，我真的很高兴
because getting something on the screen, would be quite nice, I'm really happy
我们有这个先进的系统我刚想起我没有讲的一件事是
we have this advanced system one thing that I just remembered that I didn't talk about is and it
可能会或多或少地和Window类联系在一起那就是输入系统
which will probably be more or less tied with the Window class is going to be an input system
因此我们能够收到输入事件的通知
so we have the ability to be notified about input events
但我们不能请求当前状态是什么，比如键盘上的一个键是什么，那也很重要
but we can't actually ask as to what the current state of, like a key on our keyboard is, that's going to be important as well
因为在接受活动的同时，能够说
because whilst receiving events are great, it's also really nice to be able to say
嘿，你知道吗，现在按的是鼠标左键，我们不能用系统来做这个
hey, you know, it is the left mouse button currently pressed, we can't actually do this with the system
我们能做的是接收一个鼠标事件，然后存储该事件，直到我们得到一个MouseReleasedEvent
what we could do is receive a mouse event and then store that event, until we get a MouseReleasedEvent
那样的话，我们可以保存MouseButtonPressed
and in that way, you know, we could save MouseButtonPressed
但不想在客户端这样做，我想把它转移到Hazel
but instead of doing that on the client side, I'd like to move that into Hazel
让它成为接口可以做的事情，所以我们会在未来重新调整输入事件来支持它
and just have it as something that the api can do, so we will kind of revisit input events in the future to support that
但同样，那不是一个高级的东西，那只是一个，那就像一个输入状态，输入管理器集成
but again, that's not an advances thing, that's just a, that's just like an input state, input manager conflate
不管怎样，希望你们喜欢这个视频，我们下次再见，再见
anyway, hope you guys enjoy this video, I will see you next time, goodbye